{
  "title": "Questions for G+12 and G+ Unlimited - Part 2",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 26,
      "question": "For non-cohesive soil like silty sand which dewatering technique is suitable?",
      "options": {
        "A": "deepwells",
        "B": "Flood control",
        "C": "Bypass",
        "D": "Well point system"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": "In prestressed concrete beams, the loss is due to which of the following?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Elastic shortening",
        "B": "shrinkage of concrete",
        "C": "relaxation of steel",
        "D": "All"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "question": "When the prestress is transferred to concrete in pre-tensioned concrete, the member shortens and the prestressing steel in it.",
      "options": {
        "A": "stressed",
        "B": "increase in length",
        "C": "remain same",
        "D": "shortens"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "question": "The main purpose of providing pour strip in post tensioning slab in Dubai is",
      "options": {
        "A": "to stress tendons easily",
        "B": "to separate slabs",
        "C": "water flow",
        "D": "control elastic shortening"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "question": "What is the value of poisson ratio for concrete of Pt slab?",
      "options": {
        "A": "0.3",
        "B": "0.4",
        "C": "0.25",
        "D": "0.2"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 31,
      "question": "The maximum allowable settlement in the raft foundation is",
      "options": {
        "A": "30mm",
        "B": "25mm",
        "C": "40mm",
        "D": "50mm"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 32,
      "question": "As the column height in RCC building increase, the reinforcement",
      "options": {
        "A": "increase",
        "B": "no change",
        "C": "size of column increase",
        "D": "decrease"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 33,
      "question": "In a 3 storey building, the live load of upper floors is taken by",
      "options": {
        "A": "beams and column of first floor",
        "B": "beams only",
        "C": "first slabs",
        "D": "column only"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 34,
      "question": "The final setting time of normal cement concrete is",
      "options": {
        "A": "5 hours",
        "B": "3 hours",
        "C": "7 hours",
        "D": "10 hours"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 35,
      "question": "The modulus of elasticity for concrete element is",
      "options": {
        "A": "4700xfc’",
        "B": "57000xfc’",
        "C": "5700x(fc’)0.5",
        "D": "4700x(fc’)0.5"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 36,
      "question": "As per ACI code, what is the maximum deflection for horizontal member due to live load is",
      "options": {
        "A": "L/100",
        "B": "L/240",
        "C": "L/360",
        "D": "L/180"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 37,
      "question": "The effect of liquefaction on the soil",
      "options": {
        "A": "Settlement",
        "B": "land sliding",
        "C": "loss of lateral stiffness",
        "D": "All"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 38,
      "question": "The effective length K factor for column with both ends fixed is",
      "options": {
        "A": "2",
        "B": "0.5",
        "C": "1.5",
        "D": "0.65"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 39,
      "question": "When the mixture is mixed in the plant the time should not be less than",
      "options": {
        "A": "10s",
        "B": "20s",
        "C": "30s",
        "D": "50s"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 40,
      "question": "For heavily reinforced concrete members the nominal maximum size of aggregate shall be",
      "options": {
        "A": "20mm",
        "B": "10mm",
        "C": "15mm",
        "D": "5mm"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 41,
      "question": "The strength of normal concrete primarily depends upon the",
      "options": {
        "A": "Workability",
        "B": "Aggregate ratio",
        "C": "cement content",
        "D": "W/c ratio"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 42,
      "question": "In massive structures like Corewall, concrete should be placed in",
      "options": {
        "A": "Edge layers",
        "B": "Longitudinal layers",
        "C": "Horizontal layers",
        "D": "place all in one time"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 43,
      "question": "In the case of horizontal shallow beams, concrete should preferably deposited starting from",
      "options": {
        "A": "Edge of span",
        "B": "outer portion of span",
        "C": "inner portion",
        "D": "Centre of span"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 44,
      "question": "The maximum area of tension steel in beams shall not exceed",
      "options": {
        "A": "2%",
        "B": "1%",
        "C": "1.5%",
        "D": "4%"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 45,
      "question": "We should not use longitudinal reinforcement bars in column less than 12mm",
      "options": {
        "A": "to avoid cracks",
        "B": "avoid crush",
        "C": "we can use 10mm",
        "D": "due to buckling"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 46,
      "question": "The minimum cube strength of concrete used for a prestressed member is Kg/cm2",
      "options": {
        "A": "50",
        "B": "150",
        "C": "250",
        "D": "350"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 47,
      "question": "The number of treads in a flight of stairs is equal to",
      "options": {
        "A": "risers in flight",
        "B": "riser plus 2",
        "C": "riser plus 1",
        "D": "riser minus 1"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 48,
      "question": "For initial estimate of non-cantilever beam design the width is taken as",
      "options": {
        "A": "1/15th of Span",
        "B": "Span/20",
        "C": "Span/10",
        "D": "Span/30"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 49,
      "question": "The formwork from the roof slabs excluding props can be removed only after",
      "options": {
        "A": "3 days",
        "B": "7 days",
        "C": "21 days",
        "D": "14 days"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 50,
      "question": "In fumigation process for the timber truss is cover with chemicals in tablets form for",
      "options": {
        "A": "3 days",
        "B": "48 hours",
        "C": "12 hours",
        "D": "24 hours"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    }
  ]
}
